<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<android.support.constraint.ConstraintLayout xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android"
    xmlns:app="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res-auto"
    xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools"
    android:layout_width="match_parent"
    android:layout_height="match_parent"
    tools:context="com.example.system__1.facultyinfo.cn">

    <TextView
        android:id="@+id/cn"
        android:layout_width="wrap_content"
        android:layout_height="wrap_content"
        android:layout_marginBottom="8dp"
        android:layout_marginEnd="8dp"
        android:layout_marginStart="8dp"
        android:layout_marginTop="8dp"
        android:scrollbars="vertical"
        android:textColor="#000000"
        android:text="1. Define Network?\n\n
A network is a set of devices connected by physical media links.\n
 A network is recursively is a connection of two or more nodes by a physical link or two or more networks connected by one or more nodes.\n\n
   2.What is a Link?\n\n
   At the lowest level, a network can consist of two or more computers directly connected by some physical medium such as coaxial cable or optical fiber. Such a physical medium is called as Link.\n\n
    3.What is a node?\n\n
     A network can consist of two or more computers directly connected by some physical medium such as coaxial cable or optical fiber. Such a physical medium is called as Links and the computer it connects is called as Nodes.\n\n  4.What is a gateway or Router? A node that is connected to two or more networks is commonly called as router or Gateway.\n It generally forwards message from one network to another.\n\n  5.What is point-point link?\n\n If the physical links are limited to a pair of nodes it is said to be point-point link.\n\n  6.What is Multiple Access?\n\n If the physical links are shared by more than two nodes, it is said to be Multiple Access.\n\n  7.What are the criteria necessary for an effective and efficient network?\n\n a. Performance\n    It can be measured in many ways, including transmit time and response time.\nb. Reliability\n    It is measured by frequency of failure, the time it takes a link to recover from a failure, and the network's robustness.\n c. Security \n   Security issues includes protecting data from unauthorized access and virues.\n\n  8.Name the factors that affect the performance of the network?\n\n a. Number of Users\n b. Type of transmission medium \nc. Hardware\n d. Software\n\n  9.Name the factors that affect the reliability of the network?\n\n a. Frequency of failure\n b. Recovery time of a network after a failure\n\n  10.Name the factors that affect the security of the network?\n\n a. Unauthorized Access\n b. Viruses\n\n  11.What is Protocol?\n\n A protocol is a set of rules that govern all aspects of information communication.\n\n  12.What are the key elements of protocols?\n\n The key elements of protocols are a. Syntax\n    It refers to the structure or format of the data, that is the order in which they are presented.\n b. Semantics \n   It refers to the meaning of each section of bits.\n c. Timing  \n  Timing refers to two characteristics: When data should be sent and how fast they can be sent.\n\n  13.What are the key design issues of a computer Network?\n\n a. Connectivity\n b. Cost-effective Resource Sharing\n c. Support for common Services\n d. Performance \n\n 14.Define Bandwidth and Latency? \n\nNetwork performance is measured in Bandwidth (throughput) and Latency (Delay). Bandwidth of a network is given by the number of bits that can be transmitted over the network in a certain period of time.\n Latency corresponds to how long it t5akes a message to travel from one end off a network to the other.\n It is strictly measured in terms of time.\n\n  15.Define Routing?\n\n The process of determining systematically hoe to forward messages toward the destination nodes based on its address is called routing.\n\n  16.What is a peer-peer process?\n\n The processes on each machine that communicate at a given layer are called peer-peer process.\n\n  17. Define the terms Unicasting? If the message is sent from a source to a single destination node, it is called Unicasting.\n\n  18.Define the terms Multicasting?\n\n If the message is sent to some subset of other nodes, it is called Multicasting.\n\n  19.Define the terms Broadcasting?\n\n If the message is sent to all the m nodes in the network it is called Broadcasting.\n\n  20.What is Multiplexing?\n\n Multiplexing is the set of techniques that allows the simultaneous transmission of multiple signals across a single data link.\n\n  21.Name the categories of Multiplexing?\n\n a. Frequency Division Multiplexing (FDM)\n b. Time Division Multiplexing (TDM) \n   i. Synchronous TDM\n    ii. ASynchronous TDM Or Statistical TDM.\n c. Wave Division Multiplexing (WDM)\n\n  22.List the layers of OSI(Open Systems Interconnection) model.\n a. Physical Layer\n b. Data Link Layer\n c. Network Layer\n d. Transport Layer\n e. Session Layer\n f. Presentation Layer\n g. Application Layer \n\n 23. Which layers are network support layers?\n\n a. Physical Layer\n b. Data link Layer and\n  c. Network Layers\n\n  24.Which layers are user support layers?\n\n a. Session Layer\n b. Presentation Layer and\n  c. Application Layer\n\n  25. What are the concerns of the Physical Layer?\n\n Physical layer coordinates the functions required to transmit a bit stream over a physical medium.\n a. Physical characteristics of interfaces and media\n b. Representation of bits\n c. Data rate\n d. Synchronization of bits\n e. Line configuration\n f. Physical topology\n g. Transmission mode\n\n  26. What are the responsibilities of Data Link Layer?\n\n The Data Link Layer transforms the physical layer, a raw transmission facility, to a reliable link and is responsible for node-node delivery.\n a. Framing\n b. Physical Addressing\n c. Flow Control\n d. Error Control\n e. Access Control\n\n  27.What are the responsibilities of Network Layer?\n\n The Network Layer is responsible for the source-to-destination delivery of packet possibly across multiple networks (links).\n a. Logical Addressing\n b. Routing\n\n  28.What are the responsibilities of Transport Layer?\n\n The Transport Layer is responsible for source-to-destination delivery of the entire message.\n a. Service-point Addressing\n b. Segmentation and reassembly\n c. Connection Control\n d. Flow Control\n e. Error Control\n\n  29.What are the responsibilities of Session Layer?\n\n The Session layer is the network dialog Controller.\n It establishes, maintains and synchronizes the interaction between the communicating systems.\n a. Dialog control\n b. Synchronization \n\n 30.What are the responsibilities of Presentation Layer?\n\n The Presentation layer is concerned with the syntax and semantics of the information exchanged between two systems.\n a. Translation\n b. Encryption\n c. Compression\n\n  31.What are the responsibilities of Application Layer?\n\n The Application Layer enables the user, whether human or software, to access the network.\n It provides user interfaces and support for services such as e-mail, shared database management and other types of distributed information services.\n a. Network virtual Terminal\n b. File transfer, access and Management (FTAM)\n c. Mail services\n d. Directory Services\n\n  32.What are the categories of Transmission media? \n\na. Guided Media  \n i. Twisted - Pair cable \n    1. Shielded TP    \n 2. Unshielded TP\n   ii. Coaxial Cable\n   iii. Fiber-optic cable\n b. Unguided Media\n   i. Terrestrial microwave\n   ii. Satellite Communication\n\n  33. What are the types of errors?\n\n a. Single-Bit error   In a single-bit error, only one bit in the data unit has changed \nb. Burst Error\n   A Burst error means that two or more bits in the data have changed.\n\n  34.What is Error Detection? What are its methods?\n\n Data can be corrupted during transmission. For reliable communication errors must be deducted and Corrected.\n Error Detection uses the concept of redundancy, which means adding extra bits for detecting errors at the destination. The common Error Detection methods are \n   a. Vertical Redundancy Check (VRC)\n   b. Longitudinal Redundancy Check (VRC)\n   c. Cyclic Redundancy Check (VRC)\n   d. Checksum\n\n  35.What is Redundancy?\n\n The concept of including extra information in the transmission solely for the purpose of comparison. This technique is called redundancy.\n\n  36. What is VRC?\n\n It is the most common and least expensive mechanism for Error Detection. In VRC, a parity bit is added to every data unit so that the total number of 1s becomes even for even parity. It can detect all single-bit errors.\n It can detect burst errors only if the total number of errors in each data unit is odd.\n\n  37.What is LRC?\n\n In LRC, a block of bits is divided into rows and a redundant row of bits is added to the whole block. It can detect burst errors.\n If two bits in one data unit are damaged and bits in exactly the same positions in another data unit are also damaged, the LRC checker will not detect an error.\n In LRC a redundant data unit follows n data units.\n\n  38.What is CRC?\n\n CRC, is the most powerful of the redundancy checking techniques, is based on binary division.\n\n  39.What is Checksum?\n\n Checksum is used by the higher layer protocols (TCP/IP) for error detection.\n\n  40. Define Encoder?\n\n A device or program that uses predefined algorithms to encode, or compress audio or video data for storage or transmission use.\n A circuit that is used to convert between digital video and analog video.\n\n  41. Define Decoder?\n\n A device or program that translates encoded data into its original format (e.g. it decodes the data).\n The term is often used in reference to MPEG-2 video and sound data, which must be decoded before it is output.\n\n  42.What is Framing?\n\n Framing in the data link layer separates a message from one source to a destination, or from other messages to other destinations, by adding a sender address and a destination address.\n The destination address defines where the packet has to go and the sender address helps the recipient acknowledge the receipt.\n\n  43.What is Error Control ?\n\n Error control is both error detection and error correction.\n It allows the receiver to inform the sender of any frames lost or damaged in transmission and coordinates the retransmission of those frames by the sender. In the data link layer, the term error control refers primarily to methods of error detection and retransmission. \n\n 44.What is Pipelining ?\n\n In networking and in other areas, a task is often begun before the previous task has ended. This is known as pipelining.\n\n  45. What is Sliding Window?\n\n The sliding window is an abstract concept that defines the range of sequence numbers that is the concern of the sender and receiver.\n In other words, he sender and receiver need to deal with only part of the possible sequence numbers.\n\n  46.What is Piggy Backing?\n\n A technique called piggybacking is used to improve the efficiency of the bidirectional protocols.\n When a frame is carrying data from A to B, it can also carry control information about arrived (or lost) frames from B; when a frame is carrying data from B to A, it can also carry control information about the arrived (or lost) frames from A.  \n\n47.What is subnet?\n\n A generic term for section of a large networks usually separated by a bridge or router.\n\n  48.What are the possible ways of data exchange?\n\n(i) Simplex\n (ii) Half-duplex\n (iii) Full-duplex.\n\n  49.What is RAID?\n\n A method for providing fault tolerance by using multiple hard disk drives.\n\n  50. How Gateway is different from Routers?\n\n A gateway operates at the upper levels of the OSI model and translates information between two completely different network architectures or data formats.\n\n  51. What is MAC address?\n\n  The address for a device as it is identified at the Media Access Control (MAC) layer in the network architecture.\n MAC address is usually stored in ROM on the network adapter card and is unique. \n\n 52. What is Repeater?\n\n It is also called a regenerator, it is an electronic device that operates only at physical layer.\n It receives the signal in the network before it becomes weak, regenerates the original bit pattern and puts the refreshed copy back in to the link. \n\n 53. What is Bridges?\n\n These operate both in the physical and data link layers of LANs of same type.\n They divide a larger network in to smaller segments.\n They contain logic that allow them to keep the traffic for each segment separate and thus are repeaters that relay a frame only the side of the segment containing the intended recipent and control congestion.\n\n  54. What is Routers?\n\n  They relay packets among multiple interconnected networks (i.e. LANs of different type). They operate in the physical, data link and network layers.\n They contain software that enable them to determine which of the several possible paths is the best for a particular transmission.\n\n  55. What is Gateways?\n\n  They relay packets among networks that have different protocols (e.g. between a LAN and a WAN).\n They accept a packet formatted for one protocol and convert it to a packet formatted for another protocol before forwarding it.\n They operate in all seven layers of the OSI model.\n\n  56. What is the range of addresses in the classes of internet addresses?\n\n  Class A   -       0.0.0.0   -   127.255.255.255\n Class B   -   128.0.0.0   -   191.255.255.255\n Class C   -   192.0.0.0   -   223.255.255.255 \nClass D   -   224.0.0.0   -   239.255.255.255 \nClass E   -   240.0.0.0   -   255.255.255.255 \n\n 57.What are major types of networks and explain?\n\n Server-based network: provide centralized control of network resources and rely on server computers to provide security and network administration.\n Peer-to-peer network: computers can act as both servers sharing resources and as clients using the resources.\n\n  58. What is BUS topology?\n\n In this each computer is directly connected to primary network cable in a single line.\n Advantages: Inexpensive, easy to install, simple to understand, easy to extend.\n\n  59.What is STAR topology?\n\n  In this all computers are connected using a central hub.\n Advantages: Can be inexpensive, easy to install and reconfigure and easy to trouble shoot physical problems.\n\n  60. What is RING topology? \n\n In this all computers are connected in loop.\n Advantages: All computers have equal access to network media, installation can be simple, and signal does not degrade as much as in other topologies because each computer regenerates it.\n\n  61.What is mesh network?\n\n A network in which there are multiple network links between computers to provide multiple paths for data to travel.\n\n  62.What is NIC?\n\n NIC stands for Network Interface Card. It is a peripheral card attached to the PC to connect to a network.\n Every NIC has its own MAC address that identifies the PC on the network.\n\n  63. What are the different types of networks?\n\n  Networks can be divided on the basis of area of distribution. For example:  PAN (Personal Area Network):  Its range limit is up to 10 meters. It is created for personal use. Generally personal devices are connected with this network. For example: computers, telephones, fax, printers etc. LAN (Local Area Network):  It is used for a small geographical location like office, hospital, school etc. HAN (House Area Network):  It is actually a LAN that is used within a house and used to connect homely devices like personal computers, phones, printers etc. CAN (Campus area Network):  It is a connection of devices within a campus area which links to other departments of the organization within the same campus. MAN (Metropolitan Area Network):  It is used to connect the devices which spans to large cities like metropolitan cities over a wide geographical area. WAN (Wide Area Network):  It is used over a wide geographical location that may range to connect cities and countries. GAN (Global Area Network):  It uses satellites to connect devices over global are. \n\n 64. What is IP address?\n\n IP address is a unique 32 bit software address of a computer in a network system.\n\n  65. What is private IP address? \n\nThere are three ranges of IP addresses that have been reserved for IP addresses.\n They are not valid for use on the internet.\n If you want to access internet on these private IPs, you must have to use proxy server or NAT server.\n\n  66. What is public IP address ?\n\n A public IP address is an address taken by the Internet Service Provider which facilitates you to communication on the internet.\n\n
"
        app:layout_constraintBottom_toBottomOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintEnd_toEndOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintStart_toStartOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintTop_toTopOf="parent" />
</android.support.constraint.ConstraintLayout>
